All right, let's generate a random Star Wars character so you can see here that we have swapped dev
slash API slash slash one.
And that's just going to get the first character in their database I.D. number one, is the first character
in Support Dev's database.
What if we go over to their website and we look at people for who is number four?
Uh, Darth Vader, nice.
Another common character, so that's a good one to use.
What if we wanted to get whose number, I don't know, I'm going to guess number 11 or you got to be
kidding me.
I'm on a roll here.
Anakin Skywalker.
Nice.
So, you know, keeping it in the family.
OK, so that's random ish.
Let's see what happens when we go to number 100.
There isn't a one hundred.
And so with a lot of APIs, what we can do is because this is a detail you, Earl, we can simply go
to people and this will show us all of the people.
It says there's a count of 82.
So we know there's at least 82 characters in there with an ID.
So now we need a random number between zero or not zero, but a random number between one and 82.
So we're going to create a random number const random number is equal to and this is just plain JavaScript
here.
So we're going to round whatever this number is, math.
Random.
And this is going to give us a number between zero and one, and then we're going to multiply that by
82 and make sure that that's rounded.
So if it's like zero point four, one five two three, it's going to multiply that by 82 and then round
that to a whole number.
Then we can take that number and we can turn this into a template literal instead of a regular string,
and we can throw this variable in here again, this is just regular JavaScript at this point.
And what this is going to do is get a random number between one and eighty two, and so every time we
click this, every time we click this function, this click event is going to create a new random number,
create a new random you URL and it's going to fetch that you URL and then set that data for us.
And every time that data is set, our page updates automatically.
So let's go ahead and take a look at this to refresh random character, one is Ben.
And every time I click this, it gets a new character.
So now we actually have this up and running now we still have a few things to work with, such as the
film's OK.
If there's multiple films, let's find one that has multiple films.
Here's a good one.
See three films in every film that they have in their database.
This is one long string.
What we want to do is actually show this as maybe a link and turn this into a link as well.
So let's go ahead.
And first of all, in the next lesson, let's create a link here.
I'll show you how to do that.
And then in the lesson after that, let's go ahead and turn this into multiple bullet points.